# **CARLOS NETO**

### **DEVOPS ENGINEER**

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c-neto/

https://github.com/augustoliks

**9** Brazil - São Paulo

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

Ownership mindset IT professional, with tech skills in Programming, Documentation, and DevOps.

It is a Python programming specialist, experienced in Amazon Web Services, focused on system provisioning, automation scripts, and managing logs pipelines and observability stacks.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## **DevOps Engineer**

## **Trustly Inc. | Online Banking Payments**

Movember 2021 - Current

**♀** Remote

DevOps Engineer focused on Cloud programming tasks and log pipelines development. Responsible for automation and Cloud components configuration in a world system-wide online banking platform.

#### Main tasks carried out:

- Automation scripts with Python and Bash;
- OpenSearch Cluster Management (RBAC, ISM Policies, Templates);
- Logstash Log Pipelines (Enriching, Grok);
- AWS Resources Analysis and Configuration;
- Knowledge Base Documentation.

#### Software Developer

## Fotosensores | Speed Camera Systems

April, 2018 - October, 2021

**♀** On-site

Software Developer focused on In-House infrastructure demands. Responsible for microservices development, system provisioning, and observability in a regional system-wide Speed Camera System.

## Main tasks carried out:

- Python Microservices, scripts, and integrations;
- GitLab CI/CD Pipelines;
- Observability and Monitoring with Zabbix, Prometheus, and Grafana;
- Linux Servers management and packing (Red Hat based);
- Knowledge Base Documentation.

#### **PROJECTS**

- **SFTP Cluster (Trustly Inc.)**: High available SFTP Server with users setup provisioned by Ansible and deployement over Kubernetes;
- OpenSearch RBAC (Trustly Inc.): RBAC roles provisioned by OpenSearch Security Plugin based on Principle of Least Privilege;
- Image Transmissions Module (Fotosensores): Speed camera systems module to send vehicle images with integrity and cryptography built;
- Speed Camera Monitoring System (Fotosensores): Web system focused on speed camera system components observability.

#### **EDUCATION**

Analisys and Development System (High-Education)

**FATEC - São José dos Campos** 

# July 2016 - July 2019

Computer Network (Full-Certified) ETEC - Cônego José Bento

m February 2016 - July 2017

Industrial Automation (Full-Certified)

ITJ - Instituto de Tecnologia de Jacareí

February 2013 - December 2015

- GitLab Certified Associate Gitlab Inc;
- Python Formation Certified Alura;
- Fluent Pyhon Book.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming

Python Bash

Cloud

AWS

• CI/CD

GitLab | Github | TravisCI

· Observability and Monitoring

Grafana Zabbix Prometheus

Containers

Kubernetes Docker

cker Podman

Promtail

Loki

Infrastructure as a Code

Ansible Terraform

Logs Pipeline

Logstash Rsyslog

Messaging

RabbitMQ ZeroMQ Redis